: Developer :: Programmer :: Software Engineer :: Product Owner :: Leader :: Partner :

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

As a Web Developer with experience in Product Management, I have a unique perspective from both sides of the field. I excel at developing strong and thoughtful products with organized and sustainable code as well as working with a wide range of personalities to create driven ad-hoc teams around me.

TECHNICAL TALENT

: Git :: HTML5 :: CSS :: SASS :: JavaScript :: jQuery :: Angular :: Bootstrap :: Materialize :: Node.js :: Express.js :: Sequelize :: SQL/PostgreSQL :: Ruby :: Rails :: MongoDB :: APIs :: Gulp :

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified SCRUM Product Owner	Nov 2015
UW Software Product Management Certification	May 2015
UW Product Management Certification	May 2011

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer General Assembly

May 2016 – Aug 2016 Seattle, WA

As a full-stack developer, I set up varied organized and scalable products using stacks such as Ruby/Rails with SQL, Angular/Express/Node.js/SQL & MongoDB. See projects I have done on my portfolio site, kristacalderon.com. Highlights of my skill set include:

- : Built full-stack applications with normalized databases, model-view-controller based environments, using RESTfull routes and DRY coding concepts.
- : Used code to analyze data from APIs and databases to calculate required datasets for front-end execution.
- : Planned new applications from wireframes to features to code organization to database tables and prioritized accordingly to deliver fully functioning projects with rare bugs in less than 5 days.

Product Manager Virtuoso, LTD.

May 2015 – April 2016 Seattle, WA

As the owner of product sustainability and improvement and partner to the sustainment developers and Quality Assurance team, I set a standard for high quality bug resolution and we all worked together to resolve internal and client facing bugs with timely and effective solutions. Highlights of my skillset include:

- : Wrote specs for new website features and worked one on one with the developer and tester to deliver
- : Verified and prioritized outstanding website product defects then tested all defect development solutions to confirm solutions met product requirements
- : Partnered with the sustainment development team providing industry knowledge support and product specification clarification
- : Communicated with services and other departments on status and solutions provided to resolve outstanding client facing issues

: Developer :: Programmer :: Software Engineer :: Product Owner :: Leader :: Partner :

Product Manager
Client Service Manager
National Research Corporation

September 2012 – Present July 2011 – September 2012 Seattle, WA

As the owner of a smaller set of company products, I had a level of autonomy to researched new regulations and re-designed data visualizations and layouts to create more meaningful quality reporting for products worth up to \$375K annually. Highlights of my skillset include:

:: Product Planning and Analysis:

- : Gathered and compiled client requirements from data analysis and sales and service department feedback then created effective and detailed user stories with/for development teams and built product design and revision requirements and wireframes using Axure, MS Excel, and Snagit.
- : Consulted with Lead Developers to determine technical requirements for a new reporting database and data collection and delivery process through APIs and FTPs.
- : Used Agile methodologies to develop client-specific product and ROI improvements.

:: Project Management:

- : Determined internal product position and alignment with company goals and plans through communication and collaboration with all departments, including the service team, the development team, and business leaders.
- : Detailed and evaluated necessary time and resources for projects while prioritizing workload and addressing knowledge gaps during weekly project meetings with company leadership.
- : Organized and led a team of two developers creating a subscription tool which automatically delivered reports and survey responses to client e-mail addresses.

:: Delivery and Release:

- : Wrote and updated internal specification documents and external report interpretation guides detailing client-specific calculations, assumptions, and relevant patient populations.
- : Trained staff, including client service managers, sales representatives and account managers, on individual and client-specific product design, use, and history, as well as industry trends.
- : Designed and delivered quarterly client-facing webinars detailing industry and product updates.

NON-TECHNICAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Seattle's Best Coffee, Barista Supervisor Target Corporation, Client Service Team Lead Anuban Khon Kaen School, TESOL Teacher Capital Group Companies, Client Service Representative Jan '08 – Mar '09, Oct '10 – Jul '11 November 2009 – October 2010 April 2009 – August 2009 June 2006 – December 2007

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), International Affairs – GPA: 3.83 Florida State University

Graduated May 2006 Tallahassee, FL